<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Software development, Bytes and Bates]]></title>
  <link href="https://pawelj.co.uk/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="https://pawelj.co.uk/"/>
  <updated>2015-04-10T10:25:16+01:00</updated>
  <id>https://pawelj.co.uk/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[peel3r]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[p@weljakubowski.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Just Start Blogging]]></title>
    <link href="https://pawelj.co.uk/2015/04/10/not-so-easy-challenging/"/>
    <updated>2015-04-10T09:40:19+01:00</updated>
    <id>https://pawelj.co.uk/2015/04/10/not-so-easy-challenging</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This should be and probably is my first post.</p>

<p>I decided to write this blog for several reasons.
  - to become a well recognized software developer.</p>

<p>  Why I think a well recognized developer should write a blog?
      I think it is very simple: to be recognized in a field one has to build the online presence.</p>

<p>  For several days I tried to write a well formed blog post about ? What I&rsquo;m doing right now - appeared to me the easiest way to start.
      But I&rsquo;m doing ordinary things and writing another blog, blog-post about &lsquo;How to configure my ~/vimrc file&rsquo; wasn&rsquo;t appealing to me.
      For several days I tried, thought about something that could drive me, push me to write a decent professional blog. The only thing
      coming to my mind was that it is not going to be easy - at least for me.</p>

<p>  Nothing. Still nothing. But I want to be a well grounded programmer.
      I came with another idea why write a blog and what could drive me for it.</p>

<p>  Documenting what I&rsquo;m developing, learning would help me to retain it, rethink, and possibly improve,
      make it better, push, drive me in to the programming heights. At the end it is what I want.
      By saying that I think this blog will be about my programming mainly, about what I&rsquo;m learning,
      what I want to remember and everything what is important to me.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Quickly Set Up a Professional Blog]]></title>
    <link href="https://pawelj.co.uk/2015/03/29/how-to-quickly-set-up-a-professional-blog/"/>
    <updated>2015-03-29T20:05:59+01:00</updated>
    <id>https://pawelj.co.uk/2015/03/29/how-to-quickly-set-up-a-professional-blog</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I needed a simple personal, professional blog.
There is plenty of solutions right behind the corner - one can said.</p>

<p>True.</p>

<blockquote><p>But I didn&#8217;t want  any can have solution I wanted something more sophidticated<br/>that not any one can have - many but not anyone.</p></blockquote>


<!-- more -->


<h1>Requirements</h1>

<ul>
<li>It can&rsquo;t be a Wordpress or Blogger.</li>
<li>I don&rsquo;t want it to heavy - like  Rails or Sinatra.</li>
<li>I don&rsquo;t want to have a database.</li>
<li>I want to host it for free.</li>
<li>It has to be some  how geeky.</li>
<li>Easy to deploy but showing already some of my software or web dewelopment skills.</li>
</ul>


<p>I had 2 options in my mind either Jekyll or Ghost
I&rsquo;m a Ruby developer then Jekyll was my natural choice as Ghost is written in
Python.</p>

<p>Jekyll is a simple, static site generator with the possibility to be easilly
deployed to and hosted on GitHub&rsquo;s servers for free.</p>

<h1>Quick blog deployment using Octopress - a framework designed for Jekyll</h1>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
